A Catalog of Instrumental Music Published Before ca. 1800 in the Alexander Mackay-Smith Collection of the University of Virginia
University of Virginia Library
- SIX SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICORD OR VIOLONCELLO Compos'd by Sigr. CARLO ANTONIO CAMPIONI. OPERA I. [changed in MS to read: "IV"] London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had for two Violins and a Bass [list of works beginning
  Trio sonatas, op. 4; Campioni, Carlo Antonio, 1720-1788; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Minuet; C; D; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 9/8; Adagio; Adagio assai; Allegretto; Allegretto grazioso; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro spiritoso; Andante; Andante grazioso; Andante non troppo; Andante adagio; Largo andante; Minuet; Vivace; Vivace assai
  Smith-Humphries, no. 302.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICORD OR VIOLONCELLO Compos'd by Sigr. CARLO ANTONIO CAMPIONI. OPERA I. [changed in MS to read: "IV"] London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catherine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had for two Violins and a Bass [list of works beginning with: "Sixty four Overtures from all Mr. Handel's Operas & Oratorios for Violins in Four Parts for ye use of small Concerts." and ending with: "Bononcinis 12 Sonatas"], ca. 1762?; C643; Three parts, folio, 251x181 (265x188): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-16. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-15. Blank, [16]. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-14.
  Trio sonatas, op. 4; Campioni, Carlo Antonio, 1720-1788; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England)
  Same as Smith-Humphries' no. 302.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICORD or VIOLONCELLO Compos'd by Sigr. CARLO ANTONIO CAMPIONI. OPERA V Just Publish'd by the same Author. [list of works beginning with: "Gasparo Fritz Sonatas Op. 3za." and ending with: "& Wagenseil's Symphonys. For Violins F. H. &c. 8 Parts."], ca. 1765; C655; Three parts, quarto, 250x180 (262x187): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10]. BASSO: Same as SECONDO.
  Minuet non Presto 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 5; Campioni, Carlo Antonio, 1720-1788; London (England); Minuet; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Adagio; Adagio sostenuto; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro con spirito; Allegro moderato; Grazioso; Minuet; Minuet non presto; Vivace
  Smith-Humphries, no. 306.
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICORD or VIOLONCELLO Compos'd by Sigr. CARLO ANTONIO CAMPIONI. OPERA V [changed in MS to read: "VI"] Just Publish'd by the same Author. [list of works beginning with: "Gasparo Fritz Sonatas Op. 3za." and ending with: "& Wagenseil's Symphonys. For Violins F. H. &c. 8 Parts."], 1765; C659; Three parts, quarto, 250x180 (262x187): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Catalogue [Smith-Humphries no. 27], p. [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-11. Blank, [12].
  Tempo di Menuet 3/8
  Comodo ma con Spirito 2/4
  Menuetto Cromatico 3/4
  Andante Largo C
  Andante Moderato 2/4
  Allegro non troppo C
  Trio sonatas, op. 6; Campioni, Carlo Antonio, 1720-1788; London (England); Fugue; Minuet; D; F; C; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Allegro con spirito; Allegro non troppo; Andante; Andante largo; Andante moderato; Comodo ma con spirito; Fuga; Larghetto; Menuetto; Menuetto cromatico; Presto; Tempo di menuet; Tempo di menuetto
  Smith-Humphries, no. 308. Announced in
  , September 13, 1765.
  Sonata VI is by Anton Filtz, no. 6 of his "Sei Sonate a tre, due Violini e Basso, opera III" (see See
  Constantin Floros, "Carlo Antonio Campioni als Instrumentalkomponist," Ph.D. diss., Vienna, 1955
  , p. 102).
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SONATE da CAMERA a Violino, e Violone, o Cembalo Dedicate All'Illustrissimo ed Eccellentissimo Signore il Sig: Duca di RUTLAND, Marchese di Granby, Conte di Rutland, Baron Roos di Hamlake, Trusbut e Belvoir, e Baron Maners di Haddon, Luogotenente & Custos Rotulorum della Contea di Leicester, Cancelliero della Ducea di Lancastro, Consigliero Privato di S.M. Britannica &c. &c. e Cavaliere del Nobilissmo: Ordine della Giartiera Da Gio: Stefano Carbonell., 1729; C982; Score, quarto, 280x226 (282x228): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-65. Blank, [66].
  Sonata II d
  Aria 3/8
  Sonata III E
  Sonata IV g
  Sonata V c
  Sonata VI A
  Sonata VII a
  Largo 12/8
  Siciliana 12/8
  Sonata X g
  Sonata XI A
  Sonata XII b
  Aria C|
  Sonatas, violin, continuo; Carbonelli, Giovanni Stefano, d. 1772; Aria; Jig; Siciliana; A; D; E; G; B; C; 12/8; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Andante; Aria; Giga; Largo; Presto; Siciliana; [no indication]
  BUCEM gives London as the place of publication.
- SUONATE a Tre Due Violini e Violone Col Basso per l'Organo Da ANTONIO CARELIO MESSENESE Opera Prima a Amsterdam Chez ESTIENNE ROGER Marchand libraire., 1702; C1043; Four parts, folio, 235x174 (301x182): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-21. Blank, [22]. Violino Secondo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-18. Violone o Arciliuto: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-17. Blank, [18]. Organo: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-18. "1710" added in MS between "Opera Prima" and "a Amsterdam" and again between "a Amsterdam" and "Chez Estienne Roger" on title-page of Violino Primo. "1710" added in MS after "Opera Prima" on title-page of Violone o Arcileuto and of Organo. Title-page of Violino Secondo signed: "Antonio Carello"; all other title-pages signed: "Carello".
  spiritoso 3/4
  Sonata II G
  Spiritoso 3/8
  Sonata III C
  Sonata IV F
  Sonata V B♭
  Adagio e staccato 3/4
  Sonata VII g
  Largo e staccato 3/4
  spiritoso 3/8
  Sonata VIII d
  Adagio assai 3/2
  Sonata IX c
  spritoso e Presto C
  Sonata X F
  Largo e staccato C
  Sonata XII e
  Largo e staccato 3/[4]
  Andante e staccato C
  Presto e spiritoso C
  Trio sonatas, op. 1; Carelio, Antonio; Roger, Estienne, 1665-1722; Amsterdam (Netherlands); A; B♭; C; D; F; G; E; 12/8; 2; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; Adagio; Adagio assai; Adagio e staccato; Allegro; Andante; Andante e staccato; Grave; Largo; Largo e staccato; Presto; Presto e spiritoso; Spiritoso; Vivace; Spiritoso e presto
  Lesure/Bibliographie, p. 42
  Announced in Vairasse.
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Violone o Arciliuto
  - Organo
- Six SONATAS or TRIOS for three VIOLONCELLOS or two VIOLINS and a BASS Dedicated to Signora Leonora Saluadori. Compos'd by Giacob Baseui detto Ceruetto. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catharine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had For the Violoncello [list of works beginning with: "Porporas Sonatas" and ending with: "Humphries Sonatas"], 1741; C1722; Three parts, folio, 259x181 (270x191): VIOLINO PRIMO O VIOLONCELLO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-8. VIOLINO SECONDO O VIOLONCELLO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10]. BASSO O CEMBALO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-10.
  Minueto Primo Comodo 3/4
  Minueto Primo 3/4
  Comodo 3/8
  Adagio assai 3/4
  Allegro Comodo 3/4
  SONATA VI c
  Alla Breve C|
  Sonatas, violoncellos (3), op. 1; Cervetto, Giacobbe, 1682-1783; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Minuet; A; B♭; C; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Adagio; Adagio assai; Alla breve; Allegro; Allegro comodo; Comodo; Largo; Minueto primo; Minueto primo comodo; Vivace
  Smith-Humphries, no. 349.
  London Daily Post
  , April 1, 1741.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO O VIOLONCELLO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO O VIOLONCELLO
  - BASSO O CEMBALO
- Six Trio's four for a VIOLIN, TENOR, and Violoncello-obligato, and two for two Violins & Violoncello obligato. most humbly Dedicated to the Right Honorable Lord Viscount Courtenay Composed by Wm. Churchill; Op: prima Price s/: 6. LONDON. Smith Sculpsit Printed & sold by J. PRESTON at his Music Warehouse No. 97, Strand., ca. 1785; C2113; Three parts, quarto, 243x180 (248x185): VIOLINO: Title, verso blank. "NEW MUSIC Engraved, Printed & Sold by JOHN PRESTON, at his Music-Warehouse, No. 97, STRAND.", [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLA: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, 2-13. Blank, [14]. Pages 6-7 (TRIO III) and 10-11 (TRIO V) have heading: VIOLINO SECONDO. VIOLONCELLO: Same as VIOLA. Unfigured.
  TRIO I F
  Rondo Allo. 6/8
  TRIO II A
  Rondo Allegretto C
  Rondo Allto. C
  TRIO IV B♭
  Minuetto con Variazione 3/4
  TRIO V C
  Rondo Allegro 6/8
  TRIO VI E
  Allo. con Spirito C
  Trios, op. 1; Churchill, William, fl. 1785-1795; Preston, J.; Preston, John; Smith; Preston, J.; Preston, John; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; Variations; A; B♭; C; E; F; G; 3/4; 6/8; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro con spirito; Andante; Minuetto con variazione; Rondo allegretto; Rondo allegro
  - VIOLINO
  - VIOLA
  - VIOLONCELLO
- SIX SONATAS for two VIOLINS with a THOROUGH BASS for the HARPSICHORD, Composed by Sigr. Vincenzo Ciampi Opera Prima Printed for J. Johnson facing Bow Church in Cheapside, LONDON. where may be had, [list of works beginning with: "12 Concertos for the Organ with Instrmental Parts, composed by Mr. Felton, Opera prima & 2a" and ending with: "6 Concertos in 7 parts by Mr. John Hebden"], 1751; C2134; Three parts. folio, 264x189 (275x198): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-16. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. VIOLONCELLO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14].
  Largo Staccato C
  Minuet Andantino 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 1 (Johnson); Ciampi, Vincenzo Legrenzio, 1719-1762; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; London (England); Fugue; Jig; Minuet; A; B♭; C; D; E; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Fuga allegro; Giga allegro; Grave; Largo; Largo staccato; Minuet andantino
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - VIOLONCELLO
- SIX SONATAS for two VIOLINS or GERMAN FLUTES with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICHORD. Composed by Sigr. VINCENZO CIAMPI. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catharine Street in the Strand Of whom may be had Just Publish'd for CONCERTS [list of works beginning with: "Handel's 60 Overtures, 8 Parts" and ending with: "Stanley's Concertos"], ca. 1751-1755?; C2135 incorrectly combines Walsh's op. 1 and op. 2 publications.; Three parts, folio, 246x173 (253x183): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. SECONDO: Same as PRIMO. BASSO: Same as PRIMO.
  Minuet Andante 3/8
  Minuet Andante 3/4
  Adagio 6/8
  Minuet Andante Staccato 3/4
  Adagio C|
  Minuet Andantino 3/8
  Trio sonatas,op. 1 (Walsh); Ciampi, Vincenzo Legrenzio, 1719-1762; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Jig; Minuet; A; C; D; G; 12/8; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Giga allegro; Grave; Minuet andante; Minuet andante staccato; Minuet andantino
  Dennis Libby, "Ciampi, Vincenzo," The New Grove, v. 4, p. 387.
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS for two VIOLINS with a THOROUGH BASS for the HARPSICHORD, Composed by Sigr. Vincenzo Ciampi Opera Seconda Printed for J. Johnson facing Bow Church in Cheapside, LONDON. where may be had, [list of works beginning with: "12 Concertos for the Organ with Instrmental Parts, composed by Mr. Felton, Opera prima & 2a" and ending with: "6 Concertos in 7 parts by Mr. John Hebden"], ca. 1752; C2136; Three parts, folio, 264x189 (275x198): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-16. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. VIOLONCELLO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. The title-page was engraved from the same plate as no. 71. "Opera Seconda" runs over onto the double line at the right; these are the only words changed on the original plate of no. 71.
  Giga Allegretto 12/8
  Barcarola Veneziana Allegro ma non Presto 6/8
  Trio sonatas, op. 2 (Johnson); Ciampi, Vincenzo Legrenzio, 1719-1762; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; London (England); Jig; Minuet; C; E♭; F; G; D; 12/8; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro assai; Barcarola veneziana allegro ma non presto; Giga allegretto; Grave; Largo; Largo staccato; Minuet andante; Minuet andantino
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - VIOLONCELLO
- SIX SONATAS for two VIOLINS or GERMAN FLUTES with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICHORD. Composed by Sigr. VINCENZO CIAMPI. Opera Secondo. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catharine Street in the Strand Of whom may be had Just Publish'd For CONCERTS [list of works beginning with: "Handel's 60 Overtures, 8 Parts" and ending with: "Stanley's Concertos"], ca. 1755; C2135 incorrectly combines Walsh's op. 1 and op. 2 publications.; Three parts, folio, 240x172 (251x181): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. SECONDO: Same as PRIMO. BASSO: Same as PRIMO.
  Grave 6/8
  March Allegro 6/8
  Allegro ma non Presto C
  Minuet Andante Grazioso 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 2 (Walsh); Ciampi, Vincenzo Legrenzio, 1719-1762; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Jig; March; Minuet; A; C; D; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro ma non presto; Andante; Andante grazioso; Giga allegro; Grave; March allegro; Minuet andante; Minuet andante grazioso
  Smith-Humphries, no. 372.
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS for two VIOLINS and a BASS, Dedicated to the Right Honourable the EARL of PEMBROOK Composed by Gianbattista Cirri Opera Quarta LONDON Printed for the Author and to be had at Welcker's Musick Shop Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho where may be had Six Symphonys with French Horns &c Six Solos for a Violoncello and Six Duets for a Violoncello and Violin all by the same Author NB Just Publish'd the Opera of the Royal Shepherd likewise the Overture in Parts, 1764; C2512; Three parts, folio, 247x181 (271x190): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Letter of dedication, verso blank, [i-ii]. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO.
  Larghetto 2/4
  Allegretto Rondeau 3/8
  Andante piu tosto Ado. C|
  Rondeau Allegretto 3/4
  Andante Affettuoso C|
  Allegro molto C
  Allegro mà non tanto C
  Trio sonatas, op. 4; Cirri, Giovanni Battista, 1724-1808; Welcker's Musick Shop; London (England); Rondo; A; B♭; D; F; G; C; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Adagio; Allegretto; Allegretto rondeau; Allegro; Allegro ma non troppo; Allegro molto; Allegro mà non tanto; Andante affettuoso; Andante piu tosto adagio; Andantino; Larghetto; Rondeau allegretto
  Peter Welcker published the vocal score and overture to George Rush's Royal Shepherd, announced on the title-page, in the same year (BUCEM).
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS 2 for two VIOLINS and a BASS 2 for two FLUTES and a BASS 2 for two VIOLINS a VIOLONCELLO OBLIGATO and a BASS Dedicated to His Royal Highness the DUKE of GLOSTER Composed by GIANBATISTA CIRRI OPERA VI LONDON Printed for the AUTHOR by WELCKER in Gerrard Street Soho Where may be had by the same Author [list of works beginning with: "2 Setts of Overtures and his first Set of Sonatas." and ending with: "12 by Bates & 6 collected by Tacet &c. &c. &c."], 1766; C2513 ("Violins, a Violoncello").; Three parts, quarto, 259x188 (265x190): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Pages 6-9 (SONATAS III and IV) have heading "FLAUTO PRIMO". VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-17. Blank, [18]. Pages 10-17 (SONATAS V and VI) have heading "VIOLONCELLO OBLIGATO", with two braced staves of music for violoncello and for "BASSO O CEMBALO".
  Andante Affettuoso C
  Rondò Allegretto 3/4
  Allegro non molto 2/4
  Andantino 3/8
  Adagio non lento C
  Trio sonatas, op. 6; Cirri, Giovanni Battista, 1724-1808; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; B♭; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio non lento; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Allegro non molto; Allegro non tanto; Andante; Andante affettuoso; Andantino; Minuetto; Rondò allegretto; Tempo di minuetto
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS four for 2 GERMAN-FLUTES or VIOLINS & a BASS, and two for 2 VIOLINS & a VIOLONCELLO OBLIGATO Dedicated TO HIS ROYAL HIGHNESS The Duke of Cumberland Composed by GIANBATTISTA CIRRI Musick-Master to HIS ROYAL HIGHNESS The Duke of Gloucester OPERA IX LONDON Printed by WELCKER in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho Where may be had by the same Author [list of works beginning with: "Opera 4th. Six sonatas for two Violins and a Bass" and ending with: "NB the greatest choice of New Musick &c. &c. &c. &c."], 1766; C2514; Three parts, folio, 265x194 (279x198): VIOLINO Ò FLAUTO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO Ò FLAUTO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO Ò FLAUTO PRIMO. BASSO: Title-page, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-17. Blank, [18]. Pages 10-17 (SONATAS V and VI) have heading "VIOLONCELLO OBLIGATO", with two braced staves of music for violoncello and for "Basso ò Cembalo".
  Minuetto Primo 3/4
  Minuetto Primo 3/8
  Allegro Molto C
  Andantino Amoroso C
  Maestoso non troppo Allegro C
  Largho Cantabile 2/4
  Rondò Poco allegro 2/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 9; Cirri, Giovanni Battista, 1724-1808; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; B♭; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Adagio; Adagio sostenuto; Allegretto grazioso; Allegro; Allegro molto; Allegro non troppo; Andantino amoroso; Largo cantabile; Largo; Maestoso non troppo allegro; Minuetto primo; Rondò poco allegro; Tempo di minuetto
  Owain Edwards, "Cirri, Giovanni Battista," The New Grove, v. 4, p. 410.
  BUCEM dates this as 1768.
  - VIOLINO Ò FLAUTO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO Ò FLAUTO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Three DUETS For two Performers on ONE PIANO FORTE OR Harpsichord and three SONATAS with an Accompaniment for a FLUTE or VIOLIN Humbly Dedicated to MRS LEIGH and Composed by Sigr: Clementi Opera Terza Price 10=6 LONDON Printed and Sold by JOHN WELCKER Music Seller to their MAJESTIES and all the ROYAL FAMILY No. 10 Hay Market. Where may be had all the above Authors Works. &c. &c. &c. &c., 1779; C2747; Score, oblong quarto, 196x276 (205x278): Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-47. Blank, [48]. Bound with nos. 18 and 153.
  Allo. Spiritoso C
  Rondeau Presto C|
  Tempo di Minuetto Andante 3/4
  DUETTO III G
  Allegro Spiritoso C|
  Duets, piano, op. 3; Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832; Welcker, John; Welcker, John; Welcker, John; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; B♭; C; E♭; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro spiritoso; Allegro maestoso; Presto; Rondeau allegretto; Rondeau presto; Spiritoso; Tempo di minuetto andante
  Tyson, p. 38.
  Morning Post
  , June 15, 1779.
- A COLLECTION of Airs and Marches for TWO VIOLINS or GERMAN FLUTES Some of which have Basses LONDON. Printed for & Sold by R- Bremner at the Harp & Hautboy Opposite Somerset-House in the Strand. Where may be had; [list of works beginning with: "A Collection of Scots Songs" and ending with: "Bibles Psalm Books & Prayer Books"], ca. 1765; B/II, p. 61.; Score, oblong folio, 120x174 (127x182): Title, verso blank. "INDEX", in letterpress, [i]. [Explanation of] "...Italian words used in the course of this Collection", in letterpress, [ii]. Music, pp. 1-96. Upper portion of title-page missing. Exemplar severely trimmed at edges, with some loss of text. Pages [i-ii] are oblong quarto. 38 leaves of manually-ruled music paper bound in at end; 32 leaves blank, 6 with MS music of items similar in nature to those in the printed collection, together with some songs for solo voice and keyboard. One item has note at end: "August 12th, 1802".
  72 items.
  Collection of Airs and Marches; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; Harp and Hautboy; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; London (England)
- ca. 1765, Score, oblong quarto, 120x174 (139x182): Some of the plates have been re-engraved, but the contents are identical to no. 79.
- Six SONATAS for 2 Common FLUTES or two GERMAN FLUTES and a BASS Consisting of Preludes, Allmands, Corants Sarabands, Gavotts, and Jiggs Compos'd by Mr: Wm: Corbett. Opera Quarta London Printed for I: Walsh Servant in Ordinary to his Majesty at the Harp & Hoboy in Catherine Street in the Strand and I: Hare at the Viol and Flute in Cornhill near the Royall Exchange, 1709?; C3644; Incomplete set. One part, folio, 252x167 (255x172): FLUTO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, p. 1, verso blank. Blank. Music, pp. 2-3. Blank. Music, pp. 4-6, printed on recto only, verso of each page is blank.
  Allemanda Allegro C|
  Preludio Allegro 3/4
  Allemanda Adagio C|
  Gavotta Allegro C|
  Aria Allegro 3/8
  Preludio Adagio C|
  Allemanda Vivace C|
  Preludio Adagio 3/2
  Fuga Presto C|
  Giga Presto 6/8
  SONATA V d
  Largo Preludio C
  Adagio Preludio C|
  Trio sonatas, op. 4. Book 1; Corbett, William, 1675-1748; Hare, John, d. 1725; Harp and Hoboy; Viol and Flute; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Hare, John, d. 1725; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Fugue; Allemande; Aria; Corrente; Gavotte; Jig; Prelude; Sarabande; B♭; C; G; D; 12/8; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Adagio preludio; Allemanda adagio; Allemanda allegro; Allemanda vivace; Aria allegro; Corrente allegro; Corrente vivace; Fuga presto; Gavotta allegro; Gavotta presto; Giga allegro; Giga presto; Largo; Largo preludio; Preludio adagio; Preludio allegro; Preludio largo; Sarabanda adagio; Sarabanda largo
  Not cited by Smith, who speculates that Smith no. 324 may have been Walsh's edition of the composer's "Opera Quarta Libro Secondo" originally published by L. Pippard. Perhaps the reference in
  ... The Monthly Masks of Vocal Musick... for the Year 1709
  (Smith no. 331) was to this set, the first book of op.4.
  Shelved with no. 82 to make a complete set.
  - FLUTO PRIMO
- SIX Sonata's a 3o for two FLUTES or two GERMAN FLUTES and a Bass, Consisting of Preludes, Allemands, Corants, Sarabands, Gavots & Jiggs. Dedicated to ye Right Honble. Henry Bentinck Earle of Portland, Viscount Woodstock, Baron of Cirencester, Capt. of her Majestys First Troop of Guards &c. by William Corbett. Opera Quarta. Libro Primo Enterd in ye Hall according to Act of Parlmt. Printed for ye Author, Engrav'd & Sold by L. Pippard at the Orpheus in Russell Street Covent Garden, and at other Musick Shops and at the Authors the Corner of Warder Street Old Soho, ca. 1713; C3645; Incomplete set. Two parts, folio, 295x173 (302x180): FLUTO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. [1-12], engraved on recto only. All versos are blank and unnumbered BASSO CONTINUO O VIOLONCELLO: Title, verso blank. Music, p. [1], verso blank, [2] Music, p. [3], verso blank, [4]. Blank, [5]. Music, pp. [6-7]. Blank, [8]. Music, p. [9], verso blank. Music, p. [11], verso blank, [12].
  Gigga Allegro 6/8
  Gavott Allegro C|
  Fugga Presto C|
  Gigga Fugga Presto 6/8
  Gigga Allegro 12/8
  SONATA VI
  Corente Allegro 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 4. Book 1; Corbett, William, 1675-1748; Orpheus (Firm); Pippard, L. (Luke); Pippard, L. (Luke); Pippard, L. (Luke); London (England); Corrente; Fugue; Gavotte; Jig; 12/8; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Corrente allegro; Corrente; Fuga presto; Gavott allegro; Gavotta presto; Giga allegro; Giga fuga presto
  Shelved with no. 81 to make a complete set.
  - FLUTO SECONDO
  - BASSO CONTINUO O VIOLONCELLO